Career Profile

Front end Developer with 2.5 years of web development experience. Able to effectively collaborate on small or large teams. Experience working with Agile/Scrum teams as a developer, participating in sprint ceremonies, and delivering business requirements.

Core Competencies include adaptability, creativity, critical thinking, problem solving, and troubleshooting.

Skills

React, Redux, React Hooks	HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript (ES6)	RESTful apis
Node, Express	Progressive Web Apps (PWAs)	Git, GitHub, Bitbucket
MongoDB, Mongoose, MySQL	Material UI (MUI), Bootstrap	Jira
Visual Studio Code	Webpack	Figma, Adobe XD, Photoshop
EXPERIENCE		

JPMorgan Chase & Co. | Plano, TX

Sept 2021— Present

UI/UX Developer

Implement and support APIs as a part of the API Gateway team (APIGW) in order to help facilitate smooth access and integration with JPMC API services.

- Apigee Edge and JavaScript for onboarding new partners and consumers
- Support production deployments and troubleshoot issues with consumer access
- JIRA for tracking stories and participate in all scrum ceremonies during two-week sprints
- Bitbucket for source control and peer reviews allowing for better collaboration
- Confluence for documentation, for knowledge transfers

ARGO | Richardson, TX

June 2020 — August 2021

Provides software solutions to improve mission-critical business processes for financial services and healthcare organizations by providing real-time and analytics-based software.

Application Developer II

Worked closely with project managers and fellow developers to deliver updated pages for UI Refresh efforts. Implement and maintain application features using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and ARGO's internal Browser Core Framework (BCF).

- ARGO's UI library, HTML and JavaScript for implementing updated page layouts, such as collateral pages
- Manual and scenario testing of code, design, and functionality in order to ensure a high level of quality.
- Proprietary middle tier bug fixes to maintain legacy code base.
- Created documentation to assist new team members with setting up the ARGO development environment

Elevate | Addison, TX

Sept 2019 — June 2020

Specializes in lending, offering various products for loans and lines of credit. The destination for anyone seeking to build credit and explore borrowing options.

Developer I

As a Developer I, implemented eligibility rules for an internal tool for customer service, called The Payment Flexibility Tool.

- Using .NET Core and C#, helped internal customer service determine the eligibility for the various programs of The Payment Flexibility Tool. These rules were built as part as the tool's API layer.
 - Conforming to REST using the CRUD operations to Create, Read, Update, or Delete data
- xUnit for achieving code coverage requirements by writing unit and integration tests.
- Angular 9 and TypeScript for implementing front end components such as tables and grids for the different programs for the tool.

Leo A Daly | Dallas, TX

Dec 2018 — Sept 2019

American architecture, planning, engineering, interior design and program management firm. The firm's portfolio includes projects in 91 countries, all 50 U.S. states and the District of Columbia.

Software Developer Intern

- Created pages for the migration of the public facing site to WordPress from Umbraco.
- Optimize images for the web using Photoshop.
- Improved SEO by adding relevant phrases via the Yoast plugin.
- Enhanced the intranet by implementing business card preview pages using HTML and CSS, allowing users to confirm the business card look and feel before submitting an order for their department.

Projects

tdraft (PWA, React, Redux, Hooks, MUI, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jsx)

- Simple, responsive, and mobile first text editor for the web
- Managed state with Redux and implemented the MUI FAB for the info, back, and share buttons
- Site: tdraft.io
- Code: github.com/Theobasallaje/betterletter

Employee Directory Challenge (React, Redux, Hooks, MUI, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jsx)

- Managed state with Redux and implemented MUI for cards and buttons
- Site: employee-directory-theo.herokuapp.com
- Code: github.com/Theobasallaje/employee-directory

The Oracle at Delphi (React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jsx, RESTful)

- Simple and fun site that displays random jokes from the random jokes API using GET requests
- Site: theobasallaje.github.io/the-oracle-at-delphi
- Code: github.com/Theobasallaje/the-oracle-at-delphi

Clicky Game (React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jsx) - inspired by the anime, One Punch Man

- Site: theobasallaje.github.io/clicky-game/
- Code: github.com/Theobasallaje/clicky-game

Color Game (HTML, CSS, JavaScript)

- Simple fun guessing came for RGB colors
- Site: theobasallaje.github.io/color-game/
- Code: github.com/Theobasallaje/color-game/

EDUCATION

University of Texas at Dallas | Richardson, TX | 2017

• B.S. Computer Science

Southern Methodist University | Dallas, TX | 2019

• Full Stack Web Development Certificate